<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Optical Turbulence on Maximilian Pierzyna</title>
    <link>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/tags/optical-turbulence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Optical Turbulence on Maximilian Pierzyna</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/tags/optical-turbulence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>$\Pi$-ML: A dimensional analysis-based machine learning parameterization of optical turbulence in the atmospheric surface layer</title>
      <link>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/research/2023a_piml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/research/2023a_piml/</guid>
      <description>Turbulent fluctuations of the atmospheric refraction index, so-called optical turbulence, can significantly distort propagating laser beams. Therefore, modeling the strength of these fluctuations ($C_n^2$) is highly relevant for the successful development and deployment of future free-space optical communication links. In this letter, we propose a physics-informed machine learning (ML) methodology, $\Pi$-ML, based on dimensional analysis and gradient boosting to estimate $C_n^2$. Through a systematic feature importance analysis, we identify the normalized variance of potential temperature as the dominating feature for predicting $C_n^2$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multi-physics ensemble modeling framework for reliable $C_n^2$ estimation</title>
      <link>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/research/2023b_wrf_cn2_ens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/research/2023b_wrf_cn2_ens/</guid>
      <description>Free-space optical communication (FSOC) links are considered a key technology to support the increasing needs of our connected, data-heavy world, but they are prone to disturbance through atmospheric processes such as optical turbulence. Since turbulence is highly dependent on local topographic and meteorological conditions, modeling optical turbulence strength $C_n^2$ is challenging during the design phase of an optical link or network. Over the past 25 years, $C_n^2$ parameterizations of varying complexities have been combined with various numerical weather prediction models for the spatio-temporal estimation of $C_n^2$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intercomparison of flux, gradient, and variance-based optical turbulence ($C_n^2$) parameterizations</title>
      <link>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/research/2024b_wrf_cn2_intercomp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/research/2024b_wrf_cn2_intercomp/</guid>
      <description>For free-space optical communication (FSOC) or ground-based optical astronomy, abundant data of optical turbulence strength ($C_n^2$) is imperative but typically scarce. Turbulence conditions are strongly site-dependent, so their accurate quantification requires in-situ measurements or numerical weather simulations. If $C_n^2$ is not measured directly, e.g., with a scintillometer, $C_n^2$ parameterizations must be utilized to estimate $C_n^2$ from meteorological observations or model output. Even though various such parameterizations exist in the literature, their relative performance is unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
