<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Maximilian Pierzyna</title>
    <link>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Maximilian Pierzyna</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/card/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/card/</guid>
      <description> Maximilian Pierzyna PhD Researcher Optical turbulence and satellite communication m.pierzyna@tudelft.nl +31 6 123 345 mail linkedin vcard Tip: Click the xx button above to add my contact details straight to your phone book. QR CODE </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$\Pi$-ML: A dimensional analysis-based machine learning parameterization of optical turbulence in the atmospheric surface layer</title>
      <link>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/research/2023a_piml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/research/2023a_piml/</guid>
      <description>Turbulent fluctuations of the atmospheric refraction index, so-called optical turbulence, can significantly distort propagating laser beams. Therefore, modeling the strength of these fluctuations ($C_n^2$) is highly relevant for the successful development and deployment of future free-space optical communication links. In this letter, we propose a physics-informed machine learning (ML) methodology, $\Pi$-ML, based on dimensional analysis and gradient boosting to estimate $C_n^2$. Through a systematic feature importance analysis, we identify the normalized variance of potential temperature as the dominating feature for predicting $C_n^2$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multi-physics ensemble modeling framework for reliable $C_n^2$ estimation</title>
      <link>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/research/2023b_wrf_cn2_ens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/research/2023b_wrf_cn2_ens/</guid>
      <description>Free-space optical communication (FSOC) links are considered a key technology to support the increasing needs of our connected, data-heavy world, but they are prone to disturbance through atmospheric processes such as optical turbulence. Since turbulence is highly dependent on local topographic and meteorological conditions, modeling optical turbulence strength $C_n^2$ is challenging during the design phase of an optical link or network. Over the past 25 years, $C_n^2$ parameterizations of varying complexities have been combined with various numerical weather prediction models for the spatio-temporal estimation of $C_n^2$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Availability</title>
      <link>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/agenda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/agenda/</guid>
      <description> Below you can see my availability for meetings. If you do not see an embedded Outlook calendar, please click here. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/contact/</guid>
      <description>I am happy to receive questions or inquiries via the contact form below. Alternatively, you can download my virtual business card (vCard, 1KB) with my contact details.
Your name Your email address Subject Your message Please note that this contact form uses Formspree to process the contact request. This external service uses servers outside the EU. Until the contact form is submitted, no data are transmitted to Formspree. By using this form you agree to your data being processed by Formspree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data-driven splashing threshold model for drop impact on dry smooth surfaces</title>
      <link>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/research/2021_drop_impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/research/2021_drop_impact/</guid>
      <description>We propose a data-driven threshold model to redefine the boundary between deposition and splashing for drop impact on dry smooth surfaces. The starting point is the collection and digitization of multiple experimental sources with varying impact conditions. The model is based on the theory of Riboux and Gordillo [Riboux and Gordillo, &amp;ldquo;Experiments of drops impacting a smooth solid surface: A model of the critical impact speed for drop splashing,&amp;rdquo; Phys. Rev.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intercomparison of flux, gradient, and variance-based optical turbulence ($C_n^2$) parameterizations</title>
      <link>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/research/2024b_wrf_cn2_intercomp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/research/2024b_wrf_cn2_intercomp/</guid>
      <description>For free-space optical communication (FSOC) or ground-based optical astronomy, abundant data of optical turbulence strength ($C_n^2$) is imperative but typically scarce. Turbulence conditions are strongly site-dependent, so their accurate quantification requires in-situ measurements or numerical weather simulations. If $C_n^2$ is not measured directly, e.g., with a scintillometer, $C_n^2$ parameterizations must be utilized to estimate $C_n^2$ from meteorological observations or model output. Even though various such parameterizations exist in the literature, their relative performance is unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KelpNet: Probabilistic Multi-Task Learning for Satellite-Based Kelp Forest Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/research/2024a_kelpnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/research/2024a_kelpnet/</guid>
      <description>Kelp forests are critical for marine ecosystems. They harbor a diverse range of species and maintain ecological balance, which necessitates the accurate monitoring of their evolution. We propose a multi-task ensemble deep learning framework to predict probabilistic maps of kelp forests from Landsat 7 satellite imagery. We train parallel image classification and segmentation models to achieve robust kelp predictions. Both model types are created as ensembles of 25 members producing probabilistic outputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zoom</title>
      <link>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/zoom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maximilian-pierzyna.de/zoom/</guid>
      <description>To access my personal Zoom room, please click here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
